I'm new to Buddhism, and I don't know much about it.
So I was wondering if there is a good way to learn more about Buddhism.
For people like us, can you advise us on how we can get interested and closer to Buddhism?
When you say Buddhism, there are two types.
There's Buddhism as a religion, and there's the Buddha's dharma as truth.
Generally, we call both of them Buddhism, but they very quite different in nature.
So what is Buddhism as a religion? It's similar to Christianity.
Some people go to church to pray to God. Others go to a Buddhist temple o pray to the Buddha and ask for good fortune.
This is Buddhism as a religion.
Dharma as truch implies that a pure minded person is a Buddhist monk.
Simply shaving his head and wearing grey attire does not make one a monk.
His mind has to be pure.
Likewise, a temple is not some special building but a place where pure minded people reside.
So today, if we talk about how to make money, how to be successful, who is right or wrong, this place is a lecture hall.
But if we talk about how people can be happier, this place is a temple. That is, from the perspective of truth.
Truth exists beyond the boundaries religions such as Buddhism or Christianity.
So, if you want to approach Buddhism as religion, you can go to a temple nearby.
But, if you want to approach dharma as truth.
Resenting your husband because he is stingy and won't give you enough money to spend comes from having the mind of an unenlightened being.
You can instead think that being frugal is good. You can tell youself, "Eventually, my son and I will be spending the money he saves. So, the more he saves, the better."
You can take a situation you viewed negatively in the past and see it in a positive light. This is dharma as truth.
Let me explain this according to Buddhist principles.
Thinking, "That person is bad. My husband is bad." is called Conception (Saṃjna). In this case, it is a negative conception.
Realizing that in truth, he is not a bad person, is empting your conception. Actually, conception does not exist.
Saying that person is bad is Form (Rūpa).
Sayingthat person is not bad is Emptiness (Śūnyatā).
Thus, the phrase "Form is emptiness" appears in the Heart Sutra.
So when the lady said that she doesn't like her husband because he is stingy, I said to her, "Isn't the money yours in the end and isn't it better that he is frugal than extravagant?
As we make these exchanges, she may realize that he is not such a bad person after all. This is to know the emptiness of all things.
There's no such a thing as an innately bad person. So when she starts to think positively about him, she may realize that he is a good person after all.
But emptiness does not mean that there is nothing. It means that when we look at a person in a positive light, he becomes good. This is "Emptiness itself is form."
So, instead of talking about form is this and emptiness is that,
when the lady said that her husband is bad, I said that her husband isn't a bad person. There is a Buddhist principle behind this kind of conversation.
So how do you feel now? Are you happier living with a stingy husband or living with a frugal husband?
You are happier living with a frugal husband.
If you say your husband is stingy, he becomes a bad person, and if you say he is frugal, he becomes a good person.
So, if your husband is a good person, then your son is a good son. Why? Because he is the son of a good father.
And, when you say your husband is a bad person, your son is also a bad person. Why? Because he is the son of a bad person.
It's like father like son, so the son must be bad too. Right?
Viewing your husband negatively actually makes you unhappy.
You can't make yourself happy by resolving to be happy.
Your happiness begins when you change your negative views about your husband into positive ones.
This is studying the dharma.
You can study the dharma without using Buddhist terminology.
Then, could we find such principles in the Bible? We can.
Truth exists beyond the boundaries of Christianity or Buddhism.
From a religious aspect, Christians and Buddhists cannot avoid conflict because they will argue over who is right and who is better.
My conversation with you today will be about the dharma from the perspective of truth.
You can go to a temple to study the dharma, but you can also study at home.
What did that lady say? She said she hated her husband, but since she started watching YouTube videos of my dharma talks, she is more at peace.
This mean that she is a little happier or, at least, less miserable.
So if your minset changes watching the Youtube videos at home, the place where you are sitting at that moment is a temple.
So, one method to study the dharma is to attend dharma talks like this as often as you can.
Or you can join one of the small study groups that study the dharma since it is hard to study consistently by yourself.
Christians are also welcome to join the study groups.
From the realm of the dharma as truth, it doesn’t matter whether you go to church or temple and whether you have a religion or not.
It's a place to study your mind.
So take a pamphlet on your way out to see where the study group meets.
You can attend a session, and if you like it, you can continue to study there.
If you don't like it, you are free to stop attending. You can study at home by yourself watching Youtube videos.
It that isn't enough, you can go and meet a Buddhist monk or go and study at a Buddhist temple nearby.
The truth exists in your everyday life. So, you don't have to think of it as something very difficult.
Thank you very much.